# CHOUDHURY SUJEET NANDA (1) Featured

Cloud Engineer L2 seeking roles in EC2 Instances, EBS Volumes, Cloud Computing, Active Directory, Load Balancing, Auto Scaling, Cloudformation, Requirement Gathering, Requirement Analysis, Client Management, Jenkins, AWS CLI, Git, Putty, PyCharm



Current Designation: Cloud Engineer Total Experience: 3 Year(s) 6 Month(s)

Current Company: Rigel Information Systems Pvt. Ltd. Notice Period: 15 Days or less

Current Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore Highest Degree: B.Tech/B.E. [Computers]

Pref. Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore, Chennai, Hyderabad Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Single/unmarried

Key Skills: Cloud Engineer L2, Software Developer, EC2 Instances, EBS Volumes, Cloud Computing, Active Directory, Load Balancing, Auto Scaling, Cloudformation, Requirement Gathering, Requirement Analysis, Client Management, Jenkins, AWS

CLI, Git, Putty, PyCharm

Verified: Email - id

Last Active: 20-Jan-21 Last Modified: 20-Jan-21

### Summary

Cloud Engineer with over 3 years of experience. B.Tech/B.E. in Computers.

Setup and manage various EC2 instances, EBS Volumes, Active

directories and different similar services.

Manage IAM roles and policies with minimum access with the resources and users.

Manage different logging services such as cloudtrail, cloudwatch,

Create AMIs for easy autoscaling.

Create and manage various S3 buckets and manage their life cycles.

Managed public as well as private security groups and VPCs as the guidelines of the clients.

Create topics and manage SNS service for appropriate events alerts.

Create two-tier architecture with cloudformation as laaS.

# Work Experience

### RIGEL INFORMATION SYSTEMS PVT. LTD as Cloud Engineer L2

Apr 2018 to Sep 2020

Setup and manage various EC2 instances, EBS Volumes, Active directories and different similar services.

Manage IAM roles and policies with minimum access with the resources and users.

Manage different logging services such as cloudtrail, cloudwatch,

Create AMIs for easy autoscaling.

Create and manage various S3 buckets and manage their life

Managed public as well as private security groups and VPCs as the guidelines of the clients.

Create topics and manage SNS service for appropriate events

Create two-tier architecture with cloudformation as laaS.

## Rigel Information Systems Pvt. Ltd. as Cloud Engineer

Apr 2018 to Till Date

#### Prime Focus Technologies as Media Associate Feb 2017 to Mar 2018

Work closely with the client for content delivery. Deadline rush with minimal production errors. Check grammars and spell checks and proofreading. Clients: Warner Bros., Netflix, 2D Digitals, Hotstar

#### **Education**

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Computers) from Padmanava College of Engineering in 2014

#### IT Skills

Skill Name	Version	Last Used	Experience
AWS EC2			
AWS S3			
VPC			
IAM			
CloudFront			
Aws serverless			
Route 53			
SNS			
Jenkins			
AWS CLI			
Python			
TERMINAL			
Vs code			
PUTTY			
PyCharm			
WORDPRESS			
GIT			

# Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English				
Hindi				
Oriya				

## **Affirmative Action**

Category: General

Physically Challenged: No

## **Work Authorization**

Job Type: Permanent

Employment Status: Full time